Guide to the National Ubu Roi Bake-Off Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
National Ubu Roi Bake-Off collection
2018
YCAL MSS 1145
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(1 box)
The National Ubu Roi Bake-Off Collection consists of thirty-six plays written during a grassroots event organized by the playwright Paula Vogel. The event took place on President's Day, February 19, 2018.
Vogel, Paula, 1951-
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired by gift from various sources, 2018. For more information, consult the appropriate curator.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by playwright.
National Ubu Roi Bake-Off
The National Ubu Roi Bake-Off was a grassroots event organized by playwright Paula Vogel. A bake-off is a writing exercise that requires its participants to write a piece on an assigned theme with assigned elements within 48 hours. Participants then gather and stage readings of their pieces.
On President's Day, February 19, 2018, playwrights and community members gathered for a bake-off inspired by Ubu Roi, a play by Alfred Jarry that opened and closed on December 10, 1896. Eighteen bake-offs were listed on Paula Vogel's website at locations across the United States, with one bake-off in Canada; many more informal bake-off gatherings also occurred.
Scope and Contents
The National Ubu Roi Bake-Off Collection consists of thirty-six plays written during a grassroots event organized by the playwright Paula Vogel. The event took place on President's Day, February 19, 2018.
Information about location and the affiliated event has been included where it was provided by the authors of the plays.
Playwriting; Playscripts; Plays; Theater; Vogel, Paula, 1951-; Jarry, Alfred, 1873-1907 -- Ubu roi -- Adaptations
- "Oh What a Pig You Are, Pa Ubu.", 2018-02; Bix, Karen Helfand (Box 1)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Karen Helfand Bix, 2018.
  Karen Helfand Bix
  Karen Helfand Bix is also known as Kit Bix.
  Scope and Contents
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at The Playwrights Center in Minneapolis, MN.
- "Ubu Prex.", 2018-02-19; Boerst, Matthew (Box 1)
  Gift of Matthew Boerst, 2018.
  This play was written for an Ubu Roi Bake-Off event in Minneapolis, MN.
- "A Very Stable Genius.", 2018-02; Bohannon, Sharai; Brinkley, Ben; Burbano, Diana; Burdick, Greg; Carnes, Rachael; Henry, Jordan Elizabeth (Box 1)
  Gift of Sharai Bohannon, Ben Brinkley, Diana Burbano, Greg Burdick, Rachael Carnes, and Jordan Elizabeth Henry, 2018.
  This play was written by six authors based in different locations: Sharai Bohannon (Chicago, IL), Ben Brinkley (Eugene, OR), Diana Burbano (Los Angeles, CA), Greg Burdick (Lakeland, FL), Rachael Carnes (Eugene, OR), and Jordan Elizabeth Henry (Chattanooga, TN).
- "Fuck Soup.", 2018-02-19; Brandt, Jonathan (Box 1)
  Gift of Jonathan Brandt, 2018.
- "Reality by Committee.", 2018-02; Brown, Julia M. (Box 1)
  Gift of Julia M. Brown, 2018.
- "UbuCake.", 2018-02-19; Burbano, Diana (Box 1)
  Gift of Diana Burbano, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the Center Theatre Group in Los Angeles, CA.
- "Ubu Ours.", 2018-02; Burnside, James E. (Box 1)
  Gift of James E. Burnside, 2018.
  This play was written for an Ubu Roi Bake-Off event in Austin, TX.
- "Ubu 45.", 2018-02; Cajal, Oana Maria (Box 1)
  Gift from Oana Maria Cajal, 2018.
  This play was written for an Ubu Roi Bake-Off event in Montreal, Canada.
- "Now What?", 2018-02; D'Alois, Roberta (Box 1)
  Gift from Roberta D'Alois, 2018.
  This play was written for an Ubu Roi Bake-Off event in San Francisco, CA.
- "Covfefe Roi.", 2018-02-19; Erickson, Cass; Erickson, Rollie (Box 1)
  Gift from Cass Erickson and Rollie Erickson, 2018.
- "Oedipus Pence.", 2018-02; Gilbert, Siobhan (Box 1)
  Gift of Siobhan Gilbert, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the Where Are They Going Theatre in New York, NY.
- "The Covfefe Conspiracy.", 2018-02; Glover, Katherine (Box 1)
  Gift of Katherine Glover, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the Playwrights Center.
- "Mama OO.", 2018-02-19; Goldman-Sherman, Emma (Box 1)
  Gift of Emma Goldman-Sherman, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for an Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the Stage Directors and Choreographers Society in New York, NY.
- [Untitled]., 2018-02-19; Heath, Cara Beth (Box 1)
  Gift of Cara Beth Heath, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the Victory Gardens Theater in Chicago, IL.
- "The United Nations Talk Show.", 2018-02; Hildebrandt, Bradley (Box 1)
  Gift of Bradley Hildebrandt, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the Playwrights Center in Minneapolis, MN.
- "The Giant Cheeseburger from Space.", 2018-02-19; Huszcza, Jen (Box 1)
  Gift of Jen Huszcza, 2018.
- "Feel Nothing at All Costs.", 2018-02; Jacqueline, Alayna (Box 1)
  Gift of Alayna Jacqueline, 2018.
  Alayna Jacqueline
  Alayna Jacqueline is also known as Alayna Barnes.
- "The Great American Buffet.", 2018-02; Jagernauth, Tanuja (Box 1)
  Gift of Tanuja Jagernauth, 2018.
- "How to be a Winner in the Indignation Nation.", 2018-02; Johnson, Samie Jo (Box 1)
  Gift of Samie Jo Johnson, 2018.
- "King Bubbuh.", 2018-02; Kaufman, Daniel (Box 1)
  Gift of Daniel Kaufman, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the Antaeus Theatre in Glendale, CA.
- "Miłość and the Debraining Machine.", 2018-02; Lisinski, Kassia (Box 1)
  Gift of Kassia Lisinski, 2018.
- "Make Meat Great Again.", 2018-02; Meyer, Heather (Box 1)
  Gift of Heather Meyer, 2018.
- "Coup De Grasse.", 2018-02; Miller, D. Lee (Box 1)
  Gift of D. Lee Miller, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the Dramatists Guild Foundation in New York, NY.
- "After Us the Savage God.", 2018-02; Milner, Terry (Box 1)
  Gift of Terry Milner, 2018.
- "Pere T-Rump: A Brief Deplorable.", 2018-02; Minigan, John (Box 1)
  Gift of John Minigan, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the Huntington Theatre/Boston Playwrights Theatre in Boston, MA.
- [Untitled]., 2018-02; Miroshnik, Meg (Box 1)
  Gift of Meg Miroshnik, 2018.
  No location information was provided for this play.
- "Ubu Rot.", 2018-02; Perreault, Dale (Box 1)
  Gift of Dale Perreault, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the Music Hall of the Dramatists Guild Foundation in New York, NY.
- [Untitled]., 2018-02; Poisson, Gabrielle (Box 1)
  Gift of Gabrielle Poisson, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at Yale University in New Haven, CT.
- "Pre-Ubu (or how it all began).", 2018-02-19; Polak, Brian James (Box 1)
  Gift of Brian James Polak, 2018.
- "The Consecration of Pa Ubu 45.", 2018-02; Rose, Stacey (Box 1)
  Gift of Stacey Rose, 2018.
  This play was written for an Ubu Roi Bake-Off event in Charlotte, NC.
- "Storm and Dang.", 2018-02-19; Rudnick, Eric (Box 1)
  Gift of Eric Rudnick, 2018.
  This play was written for an Ubu Roi Bake-Off event in Los Angeles, CA.
- "Turn Off Your Fucking Cellphones.", 2018-02; Sheppard, Tate (Box 1)
  Gift of Tate Sheppard, 2018.
- "Bedtime Story.", 2018-02; Teagle, Rachel (Box 1)
  Gift of Rachel Teagle, 2018.
- "Waking.", 2018-02; Wachs, Erica (Box 1)
  Gift of Erica Wachs, 2018.
- "Beleeb Meeb.", 2018-02; Watson-Jones, Brian (Box 1)
  Gift of Brian Watson-Jones, 2018.
- "An American Covefe.", 2018-02; Wegner, Zach (Box 1)
  Gift of Zach Wegner, 2018.
  This play was performed in a staged reading for the Ubu Roi Bake-Off event at the New Ohio Theater in New York, NY.
- Bake-Off information, 2018-03-22 (Box 1)
  Contains information printed off websites about the event: eight pages from Paula Vogel's website and one page from a blog post soliciting Bake-Off scripts for the collection, posted by Melissa Barton, the Curator of Prose and Drama for the Yale Collection of American Literature.